I need to come up with an attention hook
for tomorrow’s presentation.
Can you help me think of some ideas?
OK. How about using an anecdote?
People love stories.
Tell them a short story to pique their interest.
You can say “Before we begin today,
let me share a story with you.”
But I am not good at telling stories.
Can I use a quote from a famous person or book?
Of course. For example, you can say,
“There is a famous quote by Henry Ford that says,
Whether you think that you can,
or that you can’t,
you are usually right.
That is to encourage you to be confident
and think positively about yourself.
That’s a nice quote.
Can I use a question to get their attention?
Something like,“Let me start by asking you a question.”
But I don’t want to embarrass anyone
by asking the wrong question.
Yes, so remember not to ask anything too personal.
People might be offended by being asked
a personal question in public.
Is it helpful to make connections with your audience?
For example
“It’s nice to see so many familiar faces here.”
Yes, the audience will feel connected to you
and interact positively with you.
You can also tell a joke to break the ice.
For example, “everyone is gifted
but some people just never open their packages”.
Ah, that would definitely grab the audience’s attention
because you have to think twice to get that joke.
But be careful to choose an appropriate joke.
Use humor properly, or it might backfire.
Don’t overuse it.
Take this joke for example:
Do you know how much a polar bear weighs?
No. How much does a polar bear weigh?
Just enough to break the ice!
Ha, ha, ha. That’s funny.
The same as the polar bear
your attention hook shouldn’t be too heavy,
but just enough to break the ice.
Thanks. That’s a good point.
Wait! I just thought of a perfect
icebreaker for my presentation.
What is it?
Well, you’ll have to come to my
presentation tomorrow to find out.